Finding Aid for the Christine Sadler Coe Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Photographs – Presidential Families – used for America’s First Ladies and Children in the White House
  - William Howard Taft (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Woodrow Wilson (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Warren G. Harding (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Calvin Coolidge (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Herbert Hoover (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt family portrait by Fabian Bachrach (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Harry S. Truman (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Richard M. Nixon (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Gerald Ford (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - Jimmy Carter (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Ronald Reagan (no photos) (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Unidentified- negatives (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Other photographs used in research:
  - Nelly Custis Lewis (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Robert E. Lee, 1838 (from Washington-Custis –Lee Family Portraits) (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Descendants of George Washington (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - Descendants of George Washington (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Descendants of George Washington (Box 43, Folder 46)
  - The Guns of August (from a Universal Pictures film stills) book by Barbara Tuchman (Box 43, Folder 47)
  - The Guns of August (from a Universal Pictures film stills) book by Barbara Tuchman (Box 43, Folder 48)
- Flat Boxes
  - Decorated, painted and hinged wooden box with key holding a copy of the Oxford Book of English Verse (1940 – edited by Sir Arthur Quiller Couch) (Box 44)
  - Diploma – Christine Sadler- Columbia University School of Journalism, 1937 (Box 45)
  - (in Spanish from Emperador Don Carlos Ciudad de Puebla), 1952 (Box 45)
  - November 22-25, 1968 – travel with First Lady Lady Bird Johnson (Box 45)
  - March 15, 1956 – Honorary Citizen of Nashville, Signed by Mayor Ben West (Box 45)
  - October 1, 1956, Department of Defense recognition plaque (Box 45)
  - March 19, 1952 (in Spanish – distinguished visitor award to Christine Saddler for her visit to Mexico City (Box 45)
  - Original artwork by CSC (Box 45)
  - George Washington’s map of Mount Vernon- reproduction of his map drawn by him (Box 45)
  - April 27, 1978 – George Peabody College Board of Trust Life Trustee AWARD (Box 45)
  - Sadler Coat of Arms printed in green and red (Box 46)
  - Scrapbook from the 1960’s including newspaper clipping, photos, and correspondence (Box 46)
  - 2 Scrapbooks (Box 47)
    1 Scrapbook of articles and programs from the 1940s relating to CSC’s presidency of the Women’s National Press Club, 1942 -43
    2 Scrapbook 1940s included photographs, newspaper clippings, correspondence and other writings, programs Flat Box 48
  - 4 scrapbooks: (Box 48)
    1 Scrapbook of clippings from The Nashville Banner
    2 Scrapbook of articles by CSC from The Nashville Banner/ Reporters Notebook, 1935 -37
    3 Banner 1930’s articles written by Christine Sadler while she worked at the Nashville Banner during the years 1931? ---
    4 1950-1951 Trip to Denmark, Germany, Mexico and American West
  - 2 scrapbooks: (Box 49)
    - 1938–1939 – contains articles written by CSC for the Washington Post during the years 1938-1939 – gives a sense of how prolific a writer CSC was –( much rippling of the newspaper that was glued to the scrapbook pages, so these articles are not suitable for digitization), 1946-1947 – newspaper clippings, invitations, telegrams, programs, other memorabilia and items relating especially to her marriage to Richard L. Coe in 1946 (Box 49, Floder 1)
    - 8x10 black and white photographs taken from the 1946-47 Scrapbook and added to the photographs series, Photographs that are identified are from the 1946 production of Aida by the Philadelphia; La Scala Opera performed in Constitution Hall in Washington, D. C. and featuring Richard L. Coe as the 9th Spear Bearer; Other photographs of Coe can be dated to 1946-47 (probably) but events not identified. (Box 49, Floder 2)
  - Scrapbook of “Washington Column” written by CSC for The Nashville Banner in, 1942 (Box 50)
  - Oversize items: (Box 50)
    Red Carpet Club/Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce distinguished visitor
    3 black and white photographs of the Coes in the receiving line at wedding reception for Lynda
    Byrd Johnson Robb and Marine Corps Captain Charles Robb on December 9, 1967. Also pictured President and Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson.
    Inscribed photograph from Wilson W. Wyatt
  - Other items include: (Box 50)
    Diploma in Learning March 15, 1967 – 1200 mile trip through the schoolrooms of Appalachia signed by Lady Bird Johnson
    Certificate –Foreign Service Institute – Department of State, April 1967- Wives Seminar
    Crossing the Trails of Texas –Honorary order of the Texas Trail Rider signed by Lady Bird Johnson April 10, 1968
  - “Georgetown House Tour” in Sun Magazine (Baltimore) April 3, 1977 – features home of Richard and Christine Coe with accompanying letter (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - “Luci Johnson’s Engagement” by Christine Sadler in McCall’s, March 1966 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - “Menu for the Year 2000” by Christine Sadler in McCall’s, March 1968 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Cover of the Ladies Home Journal, June 1973 “As We Remember Daddy…” the very private memories of L.B.J.’s Daughters Lynda and Luci (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - New York Times “Art is not an End in itself…..” (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Articles written by CSC in these oversize folders:
    - The Nashville Banner, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - The Washington Post, 1937-1942 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - The Montreal Standard, 1942 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - McCall’s Magazine (Box 52, Folder 4)
      McCall’s Washington Newsletter, March 1942 – December 1945
      McCall’s Washington Newsletter/National Newsletter, January 1946 – January 1953
      McCall’s Women’s Club/Notes From All Over, July 1953 – October 1957
    - The Washington Post, articles on the First Ladies, January 16 – 20, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Oversize
    - Issues of the Stars and Stripes Newspaper for Servicemen during World War II, 1943-1945 (Box 53)
  - Articles and editing by Richard L. Coe
    - Contains articles in other publications by Richard L. Coe during this time
  - Folders of oversize newspaper articles on Presidents: (Box 54)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Carter, Jimmy (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia
    - Pins – (Box 55)
    - Republican National Convention –Press – Chicago, 1944 (Box 55)
    - Democratic National Convention Official Pin (Box 55)
    - DACOWITS (Box 55)
    - Press pin 1952 – Chicago (Box 55)
    - British Royal Visit- Press Pin (Box 55)
    - “Get on the Van Wagon” (Box 55)
    - Bank note- Central Bank of China (Box 55)
    - Press pass – visit of Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson to JFK Space Center, November 23, 1968 (Box 55)
    - Press pass – Discover American Trip of the First Lady, November 22-25, 1968 (Box 55)
    - Pin- Sadler is for Virginia (Box 55)
    - Autographed book sign (Box 55)
  - Oversize photographs
    - Arthur Capper (Box 55)
    - President and Mrs. Eisenhower and family (Box 55)
    - C & O Canal at Great Falls, Maryland (Box 55)
    - Fanny and Scott Hayes (Box 55)
    - President William Howard Taft with sons Charles and Robert (Box 55)
    - President and Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt with grandchildren (Box 55)
    - Mrs. Franklin D. (Eleanor) Roosevelt (Box 55)
    - Frances Perkins (Secretary of Labor under FDR) (Box 55)
    - Richard L. Coe with others (Box 55)
    - President Herbert Hoover with sons Alan and Herbert (Box 55)
    - Mrs. Woodrow Wilson and daughters Jessie, Eleanor, and Margaret (Box 55)
    - Other photographs of Presidential children – not identified (Box 55)